David Goodger

goodger@python.org · david.goodger.org · linkedin.com/in/goodger/ · Saku, Nagano, Japan

Software Engineer/Architect · Systems Engineer/Analyst · Project Manager · Trainer

Software/Systems Engineer with professional experience in the medical device industry, the financial sector, and automation/manufacturing. Experience in project management and training. Recognized expert in the Python programming language. Extensive experience with markup languages for documentation, document processing, and data interchange. Cross-platform systems development experience, ranging from GUI desktop applications to web services to command-line tools.

Strengths include: articulate, effective communication between technical and non-technical/business audiences, public speaking, excellent writing and editing skills, thorough and tenacious problem solving. International experience, with written and spoken Japanese and French.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python (expert), Perl, Lisp, Visual Basic, C, C++, SQL, Bash.

Development Methodologies: Agile (Scrum, Extreme Programming), design patterns, refactoring, TDD/test-driven development, UML.

Operating Systems: Linux/UNIX/QNX/Solaris, Windows, Mac OS X.

Documentation Technologies: XML, XSL, SGML; HTML/XHTML, CSS; Docutils/reStructuredText; Unicode; document analysis, DTD design; document data processing.

Experience

Morgan Stanley Services Canada Corp., Montréal, Québec, Canada Software Engineer, Python Subject Matter Expert (Vice President). May 2021 – May 2022

- Dynamic Languages team, Enterprise Application Infrastructure.
- Software development, including Jupyter.
 Software deployment: Python applications & packages.
- Python support & training, organization-wide.

Medtronic Inc. (formerly Corventis), Mounds View, Minnesota, USA

January 2013 – May 2020

- Principal Systems Engineer.
 Projects: SEEQ mobile cardiac telemetry patch & CareLink cardiac patient monitoring service.
- Systems & data analysis.
- Software systems requirements development.
- Agile Scrum Product Owner.

Software Engineer (Programmer/Analyst). Developed desktop GUI software for an electronic medical device system (SEEQ mobile cardiac telemetry patch). Technologies: Python, wxPython GUI toolkit, USB communication, web services, Dropbox integration.

Independent Consultant, Montréal, Québec, Canada

December 2008 – January 2013

Programmer/Analyst, Trainer, Systems Administrator. Primary client: CDP Capital.

CDP Capital Inc., Montréal, Québec, Canada

July 2005 – June 2012

Programmer/Analyst. Developed software tools for investment data analysis, including foreign exchange order management system and index fund management software. Technologies: Python, wxPython & tkInter GUI toolkits. (Full-time employee July 2005 – December 2008; consultant December 2008 – June 2012)

Python Software Foundation, remote & Chicago, Illinois, USA December 2008 – September 2009 Conference Coordinator. Chaired the PyCon 2009 & 2008 Python community conferences, working (mostly remotely) with volunteer organizers and professional meeting planners. Chaired PyCon 2008 as a volunteer. Member of the Board of Directors (elected volunteer, February 2006 – July 2009)

ELM Machine Service Inc., Cambridge, Ontario, Canada April – July 2003 Consulting Developer. Developed a control panel and data acquisition application for a PLC-based industrial gauge system, using open-source rapid application development tools (Python, wxPython, Boa Constructor).

ATS Automation Tooling Systems Inc., Cambridge, Ontario, Canada February 2000 – January 2003 Systems Administrator & Software Developer. In charge of network and server systems in a mixed (Windows & QNX) environment, office and production facility with over 100 workstations. Developed engineering data processing applications & system maintenance solutions.

Experience (continued)

Rikai Ltd., Tokyo, Japan

February 1996 – May 1998

President and Founder. Software development & information technology consulting. Primary client: Uniscope.

Uniscope, Inc., Tokyo, Japan

November 1995 – May 1998

Operations Manager & Technical Team Leader; Software Developer. Project & personnel management; research & development; analysis, design, and development of document processing, workflow, relational and object database, intranet, and internet systems; systems administration (Unix/Solaris, Windows platforms).

Embassy of Canada, Tokyo, Japan

January 1994 – November 1995

Network Systems Administrator & User Support Manager. Systems administration, user support, training, programming, & troubleshooting (150 Windows clients, Unix servers).

Gunma Prefectural Board of Education, Gunma, Japan

July 1991 – December 1993

Assistant English Teacher, Japan Exchange & Teaching Program. Taught in 3 high schools.

Open-Source Projects

Docutils: Documentation Utilities (http://docutils.sourceforge.net) — project coordinator and architect.

Polyform Puzzler (http://puzzler.sourceforge.net/) — project coordinator and architect.

The Go Tools Project (http://gotools.sourceforge.net) — project coordinator and architect.

Python (the programming language, http://www.python.org) — contributing developer; author or coauthor of several Python Enhancement Proposals (http://www.python.org/peps/).

Education & Certificates

Bachelor of Science, Major in Computer Science

1991

McGill University, Montréal, Québec, Canada

Japanese-Language Proficiency Test, Level 2

1992

Japan Foundation & Japan Educational Exchanges and Services, Tokyo, Japan

Certified Scrum Product Owner

2019

Scrum Alliance, Minneapolis, MN

Publications

Hello World! Computer Programming for Kids and Other Beginners (Manning, 2009) — Technical Editor.

Python For Dummies (Wiley, 2006) — Technical Editor.

Python Cookbook, Second Edition (O'Reilly & Associates, 2005) — contributor (section 1.23).

Python Cookbook (O'Reilly & Associates, 2002) — contributor (sections 15.4 & 2.3).

Professional Linux Programming (Wrox Press, 2000) — author of Chapter 15, "Python," a programmer's introduction to the Python programming language.

Keynote Presentations & Tutorials

Python in India — Keynote presentation at PyCon India 2010 (Bangalore, India).

wxPython I: Introduction to GUI Programming & wxPython II: GUI Programming and MVC — Tutorials at PyCon 2008 & 2010 (Chicago, Illinois & Atlanta, Georgia).

How to Become an Invited Speaker — Keynote presentation at RuPy 2009 (Poznan, Poland).

Code Like a Pythonista: Idiomatic Python — Tutorial at PyCon 2007 & OSCON 2007 (Dallas, Texas & Portland, Oregon).

Text and Data Processing — Tutorial at PyCon 2006 (Dallas, Texas).